# **ALEXIS PETERKA**

### User Experience and User Interaction Designer

telephone: 503.975.9528

email: <u>alexis.peterka@gmail.com</u>

portfolio: <a href="http://www.alexispeterka.com">http://www.alexispeterka.com</a>

## **SUMMARY**

I design user experiences and user interfaces for mobile and web applications. I'm passionate about responsive (mobile-friendly) design, accessibility, user research, and prototyping. I use Sketch, InVision, Adobe Creative Cloud, Coda 2, and lots of other fun tools.

## **EXPERIENCE**

## Teamup, Remote December 2016 - Present

#### Lead Product Designer

As the company's first designer, I work closely with the product and development team to create a culture of user-centered design. I utilize customer support feedback and direct interface with customers to conduct user interviews and usability testing that drive and validate product development.

- Took on product management role, leading sprint ceremonies and communicating team goals and results using Basecamp.
- · Redesigned large-scale CRM platform, creating style guides in InVision and Zeplin.
- Conducted customer interviews and industry research to create user personas to align feature development with customer goals.

### CrowdCompass, Portland, OR

#### March 2014 - December 2016

#### Senior User Experience Designer

Responsible for user experience of mobile and web apps with hundreds of thousands of users. Collaborated with product managers, design team, and developers to create product requirements, user stories, wireframes, mockups, and prototypes of new features. Facilitated usability testing, cross-functional design studios, surveys, and other user research.

- · Introduced usability testing program with minimal budget.
- · Mentored design interns as well as junior designers, and led cross-product initiatives, including localization.
- Used UX town halls and regular executive communications to champion design thinking throughout organization.

## Tater Tot Designs, Portland, OR

#### February 2013 - February 2014

#### User Experience Designer

Directed design of client and internal projects, taking on account management role with clients and working closely with visual designer, software developers, and mechanical engineers.

- Took initiative to build company visibility by spearheading donation-in-kind project for Portland Youth Philharmonic.
- Expanded and grew design skills on Windows 8 platform and physical product design.
- · Set up end of sprint demos to encourage transparency.

#### Freelance Designer, Kryptiq and Insignia Health

March 2012 - February 2013

As a freelancer, worked closely with management to understand their businesses and help define criteria for success of our projects.

· At Kryptiq, turned around visual redesign of client-facing demo sites and logos using Adobe Fireworks.

At Insignia Health, worked with information architects, business analysts, developers, and other designers to create the
user interface for a responsive web application that helps people start taking control of their health. We used
OmniGraffle, Adobe Photoshop, Bootstrap, .NET, and jQuery.

#### Founder and Designer, Benchmark Grading, VetLinQ, and Stayhound

January 2010 - January 2012

As one of three founders, performed customer development interviews, industry research, and was solely responsible for product design.

- Created all branding and identity for software startups using Adobe Illustrator.
- Designed and implemented all front-end user interfaces for GWT-based application using CSS positioning and XML.
- Took ownership of marketing, product development, sales, SEO, and copy writing.

#### SnapNames, Portland, OR

January 2008 - June 2010

#### Web Designer

Led and implemented all website changes, including site look-and-feel updates and application design.

- Took initiative to independently design and implement mobile version of website.
- · Organized, planned, and conducted usability testing within Agile methodology timelines.
- Proactively redesigned downloads page for high-revenue customers, increasing click-through by 135%.

#### WebMD, Portland, OR

August 2004 - January 2008

#### Web Designer

Designed and built custom websites to Fortune 500 client specifications using internal technical tools. Duties included user interface and visual design of core products. Used developer tools for coding and version control.

- Worked closely with product managers to craft UI of industry-leading health and benefits tools using AJAX, Flash, and JavaScript, as well as validating new interfaces with usability testing.
- · Created marketing toolbox of print collateral to increase usage of products and streamline sales and marketing process.

# Healthnotes, Portland, OR

January 2002 - August 2004

#### Senior Graphic Designer

Managed and implemented all changes to Cold Fusion website. Designed and maintained all online and print marketing material, customer communications, and signage. Storyboarded and implemented Flash animations to increase use of touch-screen kiosk.

- · Collaborated with executives to create compelling product interfaces, increasing sales.
- · Created email newsletters and product guides to increase customer retention.
- Worked closely with technical team to optimize load time and usability of touch-screen interactive product using image compression, Javascript, Cold Fusion, ASP, and CSS.

# **EDUCATION**

Pacific Northwest College of Art, Portland, OR

B.F.A. and continuing education classes

#### Reed College, Portland, OR

Awarded B.A. in Art